Omer Ali Abdallh

Software engineer

Dubai, United Arab Emirates MacOmeralis 2000@gmail.com +971585906465 in linkedin.com/in/omer-ali-510721190

https://github.com/omeralis Rersonal Website

Profile

Hiving 5 years of IT experience in Software Development Life -Cycle (SDLC) preparing Requirement . Developing the Front-end infrastructure using HTML,CSS3,Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery TypeScript, Angular Framework .creating Web services components of Restful Web services to interact with UI Interfaces using REST API with Laravel framework

Professional Experience

Jan 2018 - present Sabq Charity Organization

Khartoum, sudan Software Development

Provide technical support to the organization

Aug 2019 - Jan 2022 Oasis computer System

Khartoum, Sudan Full Stack Developer

> Worked on the architecture and development of an insurance aggregator application providing service to more than 5000 clients. Maintained and refactored legacy applications, improving their performance by more than 30%. Responsible for API design and development of Restful Services for the insurance products in the business Worked on building new Angular components for the customer-facing web app. interfaced with 5 customers per month to gather

requirements and resolve issues. Presided over a 30% increase in repeat business.

Nov 2018 - Aug 2020 Afromony [7]

Khartoum, Sudan Full Stack Developer

Developing electronic payment system (Morsal) and solving problems, in addition to developing

websites and electronic payment systems

Feb 2019 - Jul 2020 **Antalya Company**

Khartoum, Sudan Full Stack Developer

API and Dashboard for a Medical Broker App

Sudan University of Science and Technology - Admission and Registration Deanship Jan 2018 - Feb 2019

Admission and Registration Deanship (Department of Card) Khartoum, Suadn

Mar 2018 - Jun 2018 Call center agent MTN SUADN Khartoum, Sudan

Mar 2021 Specialized Medical Insurance Company

Khartoum, Sudan Front-End Development

Part Time

Education

Mar 2013 - Dec 2017 Bachelor's degree in Management Information System

Khartoum, Sudan Sudan University of Science and Technology

⟨♥⟩ Skills

Front-end Frameworks and Libraries

HTML5,CSS3,SCSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, TypeScript,

WebSockets.

Angular Frameworks, Responsive design.

SQL & MySQL and Oracle Database

Version control

Git on GitHub, GitLab & Microsoft Teams

Back-end Frameworks

Laravel (PHP)

basics in design Software

Adobe XD and Figma

1 / 2 Omer Ali Abdallh

Projects

CMS of Morsel payment

Afromoney Payment Report Software Development System depends on some fixes and technical support

Application Medical Insurance (Dashboard Administrator).

Computerized the health insurance system in the state of Khartoum.

Stock Management System

Point of Sale system Angular , Laravel

Salary App

Bank Aljazira salary web application Payroll Web Application Afromony Way Created

HR System

Employee life management system and everything related to financial aspects Laravel & Angular

Applus Insurance Aggregator 🛮

Insurance Brokerage Aggregator
Angular, .net Core API , C#,Sql server

AlMamoon Insurance Aggregator

Insurance Brokerage Aggregator
Angular, .net Core API, C#,Sql server

Insurance Broker System (IBS)

Insurance Broker System
.net Core MVC Razer page JQuery Dapper, Sql server ,C#
HTML . CSS. jQuery . Bootstrap

Concord-Aggregator-UI-Admin

Admin dashboard Concord Aggregator Insurance Angular Framework

Applus-Aggregator-UI-Admin

Admin dashboard Applus Aggregator Insurance Angular Framework

Almamoon-Aggregator-UI-Admin

Admin dashboard Almamoon Aggregator Insurance Angular Framework

References

Eng. Muizz Mohammed Mahdy, *Software Engineer*, Oasis Computer Systems Muizzmahdy@gmail.com, +249118441017

Eng. Akram Gorashi Sayed, *Software Engineer*, Oasis Computer Systems akramgorashi6@hotmail.com, +249925050905

Eng. Tariq Mansour, *Technical Department Manager*, Afromony +249912356709

Eng. Issara Mohmmed, *General Director*, Sabg Organization +249123273808

Omran Ibrahim, *Team Manager*, Oasis Computer System omranibrahim30@gmail.com, +249993061298

Omer Ali Abdallh 2 / 2